Ferdinand C. Latrobe papers
Ferdinand C. Latrobe papers
- Series II. Journals and Diaries, circa 1860-1988; bulk 1880-1911; 3.5 boxes (2 linear feet)
  - Subseries II.B. Account Books
    - Book containing appointments, addresses and accounts, 1898 (Box 11, Folder Envelope 5)
    - Book containing appointments, addresses, and brief diary entries (mostly relating to weather), 1899 (Box 11, Folder Envelope 6)
    - Maryland Congressional List, 1900 (Box 11, Folder Envelope 7)
    - “Detroit Stove Works” account book, 1903 (Box 11, Folder Envelope 8)
    - Standard Diary used as appointment book, 1905 (Box 11, Folder Envelope 9)
    - Account book, incomplete, 1910 (Box 11, Folder Envelope 10)
- Series III. Railroad Documents, 1830-1857; 50 documents (.25 linear feet)
  The bulk of this series contains documents pertaining to a dispute between railroad locomotive engineers, Ross Winans and Henry Tyson. This subseries contains pamphlet documents, rough drafts, and copies. It is arranged by similar subject, paper, and corresponding numbering on pages when applicable. This set of documents is not arranged alphabetically by material. The papers of the dispute all seem to be by Ross Winans promoting his side of the argument over the best locomotive engines to build and use by the B & O Railroad.
  - Series III. A. John H.B. Latrobe Letter
    - “Letter of PE Thomas, after the decision in MD Court of Appeals regards the RR Company,” by John H.B. Latrobe (2 pages). January 5, 1830. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Series III.B. Ross Winans and Henry Tyson Dispute Papers, 6 folders
    This subseries is arranged by page number, and by material size and color.
    - Winans Papers, numbered pages 1-11, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Winans Papers, numbered pages 12-26, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Winans Papers, partially finished draft, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Winans Papers, one piece, attached copy, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Winans Papers, blue paper fragments, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Winans Papers, fragments, notes, un-numbered, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)